Guide to the Davies/Scroggie Collection of Canadian Fur Trade Documents
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- December 2001 Acquisitions, 1751-1822
  - Canadian Fur Trade Documents
    - Gregory, John & Toussaint Pothier. Account of an adventure to Detroit, 1785 April 28 (Box 2)
    - Ellice, Alexander. Assignment and deed of trust, 1786 March 25 (Box 2)
    - Kay & Holt. Invoice, 1788 September 10 (Box 2)
    - Oldham, William & John Howard. Promissory note, 1792 August 16 (Box 2)
    - Desauniers-Beaubien, Antoine. Protested note issued by Pierre Labute, 1792 September 1 (Box 2)
    - Sills, Jonathan. Deposition of damaged goods, 1792 December 20 (Box 2)
    - Montour, Nicholas. Suit against John Jones, 1796 April 20 (Box 2)
    - Jourdain dit Labrosse, François. Autograph letter, signed, to Louis Jourdain, [1796] August 18 (Box 2)
    - Henry, John V. Autograph letter, signed, to James Reid, 1798 March 23 (Box 2)
    - Beaujeu, Jacques-Philippe Saveuse de. Court judgments, 1798 June-September (Box 2)
    - Minguay, Augustin. Account statements with Joseph Chartrand (three items), circa 1800 (Box 2)
    - Gibb, Benaiah. Statement of account with James Hughes, 1801 September 16 (Box 2)
    - Rousseau, Dominique & Toussaint Pothier. Partnership agreement, draft, 1802 August 19 (Box 2)
    - M'Tavish, Frobisher & Co. Claim against François Piet dit Fainant, 1802 June (Box 2)
    - M'Tavish, Frobisher & Co. Suit against Joseph Masson, 1802 (Box 2)
    - Lacroix, Isidore. Statement of account with Claude Laframboise, 1805-1806 (Box 2)
    - Finlay, James v. Austin Cuvillier. Court documents (three items), 1806-1807 (Box 2)
    - Lacroix, J. H. Statement of furs received, 1808 June 13 (Box 2)
    - Henry, Alexander, Sr. List of furs and prices realized, 1809 August 9 (Box 2)
    - Robertson, Daniel. Autograph letter, signed, to James C. Grant, 1822 March 28 (Box 2)
  - Documents Concerning the Bankruptcy of the North West Company
    Former Call Number: Uncat WA MS File Documents
    - Six partly printed documents, blanks filled in manuscript, 1826-1828 (Box 2)
- December 2003 Acquisition, 1770-1818
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 631
  Organized under two headings: Voyageur Contracts and Canadian Fur Trade Documents.
  The December 2003 Acquisition consists of three voyageur contracts (1808-1818), one document relating to a court judgement obtained by Joseph Sanguinet against Mathurin Laroche (1770), and three statements of account relating to the Canadian fur trade (1792-1796).
  - Voyageur Contracts
    - Parker, Gerrard, Ogilvy & Co., 1808 April 15; 2 (Box 2)
    - American Fur Co., 1818 March 20 (Box 2)
  - Canadian Fur Trade Documents
    - Sanguinet, Joseph. Court document, 1770 March 10 (Box 2)
    - Mittleberger, John. Statements of account to [Etienne-Charles] Campion and [Jean-Baptiste] Tabeau (two items), 1792 October 1 (Box 2)
    - Howard, Joseph. Statement of account with Nicolas Caron, 1796 November 2 (Box 2)
- December 2005 Acquisition, 1768-1808
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 840
  The December 2005 Acquisition consists of three voyageur contracts (1808) and 10 financial and legal documents relating to the Canadian fur trade (1768-1805).
  - Voyageur Contracts
    - Parker, Gerrard, Ogilvy & Co., 1808 April; 3 (Box 2)
  - Canadian Fur Trade Documents
    Not arranged in any particular order, as received by the library.
    - Legras de Rouville, Marie-Anne. Promissory note to Moses Hazen, 1768 February 10 (Box 2)
    - Sanguinet, Joseph. Claim against widow Rapin, 1770 December 18 (Box 2)
    - Grant & Laframboise. Promissory note, 1800 November 7 (Box 2)
    - [Hubert-Lacroix, Jacques]. Invoice, 1785 October 27 (Box 2)
    - Trestler, Jean-Joseph. Statement of accounts due to him by Antoine Deschamps, 1799 March 15 (Box 2)
    - M'Tavish, Frobisher & Co. Invoice, 1797 August-October (Box 2)
    - Henry, Alexander. Promissory note, 1803 October 1 (Box 2)
    - M'Tavish, Frobisher & Co. Court documents (two items), 1805 (Box 2)
    - Parker, Gerrard, Ogilvy & Co. Promissory note, 1805 September (Box 2)
- December 2006 Acquisition, 1724-1856
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 931
  The December 2006 Acquisition consists of 15 voyageur contracts (1801-1820) and 50 legal and financial documents relating to the Canadian fur trade (1724-1856).
  - Voyageur Contracts
    - M'Tavish, Frobisher & Co., 1801 March 21 (Box 3)
    - Parker, Gerrard, Ogilvy & Co., 1802 March 24 (Box 3)
    - John Ogilvy, 1802 April 23 (Box 3)
    - Parker, Gerrard, Ogilvy & Co., 1802 April 26 (Box 3)
    - Forsyth, Richardson & Co., 1806 September 16 (Box 3)
    - Forsyth, Richardson & Co., 1806 September 22 (Box 3)
    - Reuben Sherwood, 1807 February 21 (Box 3)
    - Reuben Sherwood, 1807 February 21 (Box 3)
    - Parker, Gerrard, Ogilvy & Co., 1807 March 14 (Box 3)
    - Parker, Gerrard, Ogilvy & Co., 1807 May 19 (Box 3)
    - M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays & Co. & John Ogilvy & Thomas Thain, 1811 December 21 (Box 3)
    - M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays & Co. & John Ogilvy & Thomas Thain, 1811 December 30 (Box 3)
    - M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays & Co. & John Ogilvy & Thomas Thain, 1811 December 30 (Box 3)
    - M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays & Co. & Pierre de Rocheblave, 1820 November 4 (Box 3)
    - M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays & Co. & Pierre de Rocheblave, 1820 December 15 (Box 3)
  - Canadian Fur Trade Documents
    - Véron de Grandmesnil, Étienne. Document regarding the trial of Alphonse de Tonty and Jacques-Charles Dubuisson, and the affairs of Lamothe Cadillac, 1724 (Box 3)
    - Charest, Catherine. Autograph letter, signed, to Pierre Trottier Desauniers, 1736 March 14 (Box 3)
    - Fur traders on jury duty. Court document, 1769 October 2 (Box 3)
    - Stenhouse, John and William Kay. Court document, 1773 March 30 (Box 3)
    - Malhiot, Francois & Coursolles, Jean-Marie. Statements of account (seven items), 1787-1800 (Box 3)
    - Fur trade receipts (four items), 1793-1795 (Box 3)
    - Meldrum & Park, John Askin, Leith & Shephard, and James Abbott. Receipt, circa 1800 (Box 3)
    - Frobisher, Joseph. Petition to the Court, 1799? (Box 3)
    - Ellice, Alexander. Court documents (seven items), 1799-1840 (Box 3)
    - Hallowell, William, John McKay and John Ferguson. Documents relating to an annuity for the minor children of John McKay (two items), 1803 (Box 3)
    - Sayer, John. Documents relating to land sales and holdings (seven items), 1806-1829 (Box 3)
    - Kittson, George. Statement of account with J. Godard, 1806 December 10 (Box 3)
    - Laframboise, Claude. Statements of account (three items), 1806 (Box 3)
    - Richardson, John. Autograph letter, signed, to Mrs. Martha McIntosh, 1817 June 23 (Box 3)
    - Fraser, Alexander. Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Jones, 1831 March 3 (Box 3)
    - Simson, Sir George. Document relating to the estate of George McDougall, 1856 February 15 (Box 3)
    - Unidentified, chiefly receipts (ten items), 1819-1820 (Box 3)
- December 2007 Acquisition, 1788-1800
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 995
  The December 2007 Acquisition consists of 11 legal documents relating to the Canadian fur trade (1788-1800).
  - Allen, Edward. Financial documents (two items), 1788 (Box 3)
  - M'Tavish, Simon. Legal claim, 1798 April 27 (Box 3)
  - McBeath, George. Legal documents (four items), 1800 (Box 3)
  - Corry, Mary. Legal suit for bastardry (four items), 1800 (Box 3)
- December 2008 Acquisition, 1801-1806
  Former call number: Uncat WA MS File Davies
  The December 2008 Acquisition consists of 13 voyageur contracts outfitted by M'Tavish, Frobisher & Co. (1801-1806)
  - M'Tavish, Frobisher & Co., 1801-1806 (Box 3)
- December 2009 Acquisition, 1777-1848
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 1230
  The December 2009 Acquisition consists of two voyageur contracts (1801, 1804) and eight documents and letters relating to the Canadian fur trade (1777-1848).
  - Lemoine Despins, Jacques-Joseph. Receipt for the funeral expenses of Trottier Dufy, 1777 April 19 (Box 3)
  - Announcement of the funeral of William Holmes, 1792 August 18 (Box 3)
  - Announcement of the funeral of Joseph Howard, 1797 December 7 (Box 3)
  - M'Tavish, Frobisher & Co. Voyageur contract, 1801 January 10 (Box 3)
  - M'Tavish, Frobisher & Co. Voyageur contract, 1804 January 31 (Box 3)
  - Badgley, Francis and Charles Baptiste Boue. Bankruptcy judgement, 1805 June 20 (Box 3)
  - Walker, Hamilton & Edward Walker. Power of attorney, 1814 April 30 (Box 3)
  - Hart, Benjamin. Court document, 1839 April 25 (Box 3)
  - Hart, Benjamin & Co. Protested letter of exchange, 1847 August 28 (Box 3)
  - Brandeis, Joseph. Power of attorney, 1848 March 25 (Box 3)